Love Comes To The Forest Folk . . . and to you, in one
of the world's greatest love stories!
Bambi is a animation, drama, family film directed by David Hand.
Bambi's tale unfolds from season to season as the young prince of
the forest learns about life, love, and friends.
Young Bambi (voice) (uncredited), played by Donnie Dunagan.
Young Thumper (voice) (uncredited), played by Peter Behn.
Young Flower (voice) (uncredited), played by Stan Alexander.
Young Faline (voice) (uncredited), played by Cammie King.
Friend Owl (voice) (uncredited), played by Will Wright.
Adolescent Bambi (voice) (uncredited), played by Hardie Albright.
Bambi is a 1942 American animated coming-of-age drama film produced by Walt Disney and released by RKO
Radio Pictures, loosely based on Felix Salten's 1923 novel Bambi, a Life in the Woods.
It was directed by David D.
Hand, and a team of six sequence directors.
The main characters are Bambi, a white-tailed deer; his parents (the Great Prince of the forest and his unnamed mother); his
friends Thumper (a pink-nosed cottontail rabbit) and Flower (a skunk); and his childhood friend and future mate, Faline.
In the original book, Bambi was a roe deer, a species native to Europe, but Disney
decided to base the character on a mule deer from Arrowhead, California.
Illustrator Maurice "Jake" Day convinced Disney that the mule deer had large "mule-like" ears and were more common to
western North America, but that the white-tail deer was more recognized throughout the United States.
The film received three Academy Award nominations: Best Sound (Sam Slyfield), Best Song
(for "Love Is a Song" sung by Donald Novis) and Original Music Score.
In June 2008, the American Film Institute presented a list of its "10 Top 10"—the best ten films in each of
ten classic American film genres—after polling over 1,500 people from the creative community.
Bambi attained third in animation.
In December 2011, the film was added to the National Film Registry of the Library of
Congress as being "culturally, historically and aesthetically significant".
A follow-up, Bambi II, premiered in theaters in Argentina on January 26, 2006, before being
released as a direct-to-video title in the United States on February 7, 2006.
In January 2020, it was announced that a photorealistic
computer-animated remake was set to be in development.
However, on January 2026, it was reported that the
live-action remake film had been cancelled.
The film explores themes of loss of loved one,
cartoon, forest, coming of age, best friend.
The tone is emotional.